Mary Florence O'Shea Papers
Dominican University Archives and Special Collections
Mary Florence O'Shea Papers
1864 - 2010
1943 - 1997
The O'Shea Family
6.75 linear feet
Dominican University Archives and Special Collections
A10049
None.
Materials bequeathed to Dominican University by Mary Florence O'Shea
Generally throughout the collection materials are arranged chronologically, excepting in the case of subject files and correspondence where materials are alphabetical. The whole collection is arranged chronologically, progressing from the O'Shea family papers on through each significant chapter of Mary Florence's life, in respect to her own particular organizational style.
Mary Florence O'Shea kept many photographs documenting her activities throughout her life. These photographs were not kept in a single location, nor necessarily with the relevant collections, within her home. Prints that were found with the individual collections were often stored separately. In the interest of ease of access, photographs for any given series are interfiled with the relevant papers as the final Sub-series of each given Series.
USDA, ARS, National Genetic Resources Program. Germplasm Resources Information Network - (Grin) [Online Database]. National Germplasm Resources Laboratory, Beltsville, Maryland. http://www.ars-grin.gov/cgi-bin/npgs/html/taxon.pl?452733 Web. Feb 22, 2011
Remus, William. “The Instruments for Gamelan Bali.” Web. Feb 22, 2011 http://remus.shidler.hawaii.edu/gamelan/baliinst.htm
University of Michigan, Cultural Heritage Initiative for Community Outreach. "The Glorious Gamelan." Gamelan: Venerable Lake of Honey. Web. 22 February 2011.http://www2.si.umich.edu/chico/gamelan/gamelanVT2
Mary Florence O’Shea was born September 8th, 1920. She graduated from Rosary College in 1941. From there she attended University of Chicago Teachers’ College and Loyola University from 1941 to 1943. During that same period she taught math at Wendell Phillips High School and chemistry at Marshall High School.
In 1943 she, along with her sister Mary Jane, enlisted in the Naval WAVES program, and served as a Navigation Instructor, Navigation Training Officer and Assistant Communications Officer, until 1946. Mary Florence and her sister Mary Jane were the first women ever to serve on military flight crews.
During the years of 1952-1954 she received a Fulbright Grant to teach in Burma. She taught for the State's Central High School from June 1953-1954, and was given the name Daw Myint Swe by her students and associates, who continued to use this address in their correspondence with her over the years. While in Southeast Asia she used the opportunity to visit Singapore, the Philippines, Hong Kong, Japan and Thailand, finally returning to the United States via Hawaii in April of 1954.
After returning from her travels and work in Burma, Mary Florence began work with Phillips High School. On March 14, 1955 she was transferred from Phillips High to the Hyde Park High School, an assignment which began March 14, 1955. Mary Florence was later appointed principal of Philip Murray School on September 7, 1959. She later served as principal for Luke O'Toole Elementary School from 1964 until [1985]. She retired from Chicago Public Schools on December 20th, 1985.
Mary Florence continued to travel until the early 2000s. She passed away on the 20th of February, 2010.
Mrs. B.Maley died January 28, 1896, aged 74 years old
Bernard Stokes, brother of Caroline Stokes O'Shea, died March 31, 1933.
Carrie Stokes O'Shea, Mary Florence's mother, was buried on the first of August, 1942.
Personal Names:
Margaret Aung Thwin
O'Neill, Sister Thomas Aquinas
O'Shea, Mary Jane
The Burma Studies Foundation, NIU, DeKalb, IL
The Mary Florence O'Shea Papers contain materials from four generations of her family, including items from the O'Sheas, the Stokes and the Maleys. Neither Mary Florence nor Mary Jane had children, and these papers represent the end of their familial line. The bulk of the materials come from Mary Florence's own activities, and is grouped according to each significant milestone as she accounted for them.
There are hundreds of family photos, much ephemera related to her travels and interests, with a particular emphasis on her year spent in Burma from 1953 to 1954. Also of note is her collection of photographs and ephemera from her time as the principal of Luke O'Toole School located on Chicago's south side.
Duplicate materials and moldy materials discarded. Most of the book collection transferred to the Rebecca Crown Library for processing. Slides were evaluated on a case-by-case basis and faded or discolored items were discarded. The bulk of the discarded slides were from Mary Florence's 1986 trip to China. She purchased several color slide packets of tourist destinations, all of which were severely discolored or faded.
Several hundred photographs were discarded from Mary Florence's travels, due to fading, duplication, damage, or for a lack of contextual information. Images of locations that are well-documented popularly, such as Paris, Rome, Sicily, London, etc., and which contained no intrinsic value other than as tourist photography, were also discarded. In all, 16 photograph albums were removed from the collection. A single two-volume sample of her photo album making was retained.
Select books removed to the general Special Collections book collection: The Way to Cook by Julia Child, signed to Florence; Your Irish Ancestors by J. Anderson Black placed with Mae Kennedy Kane's genealogical books; Le Vrai Visage du Padre Pio: Prêtre et Apôtre by Maria Winowska, signed to Mary Jane, placed with Fribourg book collection.
Hats and scarves transferred to the fabric department via Susan Strawn.
- Series 1: O'Shea Family
  These papers are drawn from materials left to Mary Florence by her elders and ancestors, or which come from her early childhood. The bulk of these papers concern Bernard Stokes, a veteran of the Spanish-American War, as well as Mary Florence's mother and father.
  - Maley, D. - Appointment to Sergeant, 1864 (Box FFC3, D3)
  - Maley, D. - University of Notre Dame Receipt, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Maley, Mrs. B. - Memorial Card, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - O'Shea, Albert D., 1917, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Republic of Ireland Bond Certificate #1766, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stokes, Bernard - ephemera, 1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stokes, Bernard - Correspondence, 1930 - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Edison Company Stock Certificate, 1933 - 1937 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Estate of Bernard Stokes, 1939 - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Caroline to Mrs. O'Shea, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - O'Shea, Carrie Stokes, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - O'Shea, Benjamin - Last Will and Testament, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - O'Shea Music Store, Inc., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series 1: Photographs
    - Mary Florence, Mary Jane and their parents, ca. 1910 - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Early family photographs, identified, 1933 - 1939, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Early family photographs, July, 1936, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Early family photographs, unidentified, folder 1 of 2, ca. 1890 - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Early family photographs, unidentified, folder 2 of 2, ca. 1890 - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Photo Album, 1932 - 1978, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series 2: WAVES
  All of these papers are drawn from Mary Florence and Mary Jane's years of service in the Navy, from 1943 to 1946. The bulk of the materials come from Mary Florence's scrapbook. The scrapbook detailing her WAVES years holds an abundance of correspondence, ephemera and photography related to her service.
  - Sub-series 1: Correspondence
    - Dale, Audrey, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Stewart, Rosemary J., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Navy, 1943 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sub-series 2: Chronological Files
    - Marching to Victory, fifteenth printing, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Naval Identification Cards, 1943 - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Appointment to Ensign, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Appointment to Ensign, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Mary Florence O'Shea Ensign Card, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Waves of the Navy sheet music, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Officer Service Record, 1944 - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, ca. 1944 - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Designation as Naval Aviation Observer, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Officer's Qualification Record Jacket, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Waves News Letter, December 1945, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Dead Reckoning Computer, specification AN-C-74, ca. 1940s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Honorable Discharge from the U.S. Naval Reserve, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Naval History, April 1994, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Department of Veterans' Affairs, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 3: Scrapbook
    - Scrapbook, WAVES, 1944 - 1946, n.d. (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 1-2 (see also: Oversized), ca. 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 17-18, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 27-28, 1944 - 1945 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 47-48, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 49-50, ca. 1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 51-52, ca. 1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between pg. 53-54, 1944 - 1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook, loose materials between end pages, rear(see also: Oversized), 1945 - 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sub-series 4: Ephemera
    - Buttons for Naval coat, spare, 5 total, 1943
    - Naval visor cap band with insignia, ca. 1943
    - Mary Florence O'Shea dog tag, 1944
    - Insignia Lapel Pins (10 total), ca. 1944
    - Naval Aerial Navigator Wing (2 total), ca. 1945
    - Naval Aviation Observer Wing, ca. 1945
    - [Naval Aviation Observer Wing with missing bullion], ca. 1945
    - WWII Naval Officer cap pin, ca. 1945
    - Ribbon Bar (WWII Victory Medal/WWII American Campaign Medal), ca. 1945
    - U.S. Navy Reserve Honorable Discharge pin, ca. 1954
  - Sub-series 5: Photographs
    - WAVES Photographs, 1944 - 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Burma
  Papers, notebooks, ephemera and photographs drawn from Mary Florence's year teaching for the State School in Burma.
  Mary Florence wrote extensively to her sister Mary Jane while teaching in Burma. These letters can be found in 8021 Mary Jane O'Shea Papers – Personal Papers – Correspondence.
  - Sub-series ?: Correspondence
    - Ba Shin, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ba Shin, 1953 - 1954, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Burman, Shibbal & Shellay, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Chit Ko Ko, 1955 - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Crazy Gang, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Daw Christabel Sein, 1953 - 1960 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Dot, 1953, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Harsany, Emilene, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hla Hla [Kyin] (Hilda), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - U Hla Tun Siu and Daw Shaw May, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Htun Myaing & Shella, ca. 1950s (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Josef, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Julie Thin Kyi, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Kyaw Htun, 1954 - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Kyaw Myint Kyaw, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Landry, Lionel, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Margaret Aung Thwin, 1954 - 1995, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Mosier, Mildred A., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Norma Thein Nyunt & Mandie, 1954 - 1955, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Nyunnt Nyuunt Yee, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - O'Shea, Mary Florence, to Aunt Alice and Uncle Jim, 1953 - 1954 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Sircar, Nina, 1955 - 1977, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - U Thant, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Thein Nyunt, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Tin, Richard N., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - W, Ahkwe, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Welsh, Janet, 1954, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Wolf, Frank E., to Ucho, U.S. Educational Foundation in Burma, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, empty covers, 1954 - 1962, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, general and unidentified, 1953 - 1958, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sub-series 2: Subject Files
    - American Export Lines, Inc., 1954 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Azad Photo Studio, ca. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Bristol Hotel, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Burma-America Institute, Spoken Burmese, Unit I, Revised, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - The Burma Studies Foundation - Deed of Gift, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Burma Translation Society, "Goldfish for Primary Schools", ca. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Burma Translation Society, "Weather and Climate for Primary Schools", ca. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Burmese Calendar Art, 3 sheets, 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Business Cards, ca. 1953 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Clippings - State High School and Margaret Hope Aung-Thwin, ca. 1954, n.d. (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Clippings - Conflict, Aung San Suu Kyi, and general, 1968 - 2001, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, general, 1968 - 1992, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Druitt & Stamp, "A World Geography for Schools in Burma, Part I:Burma and India, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Educational Exchange Newsletter, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Embassy of Burma, 1953 - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Exchange Control Department, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Fulbright Grant and release to teach in Burma, 1952 - 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hand-painted greeting cards, blank, ca. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - High School Final and Matriculation Examination, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Indonesia To-Day: Education and Science", Ministry of Information Diakarta, ca. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Institute of International Education - News Bulletin, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - KLM - Acolyte of Aeolus certificate, 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - License to drive a Motor-Vehicle, Burma, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - List of articles in Sea Freight, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - M. G. Kapadia & Co., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Map of Rangoon, published by U San Pe, ca. 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Map of Southeast Asia, ca. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Ministry of Education - Educational Plan for a Welfare State, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Notebook, "Prome Road, 1953", 1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Notebook (black cover), ca. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Notebook -"Conflict of Pakistan + India", ca. 1950s (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Notes and Jounrals from Burma, 1953 - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Officers of the Department of Education, Headquarters, Rangoon, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Painted panels, [stories the Ramikian], 4 total, ca. 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Paintings - Larban, [ethnic groups of Burma], 7 total, ca. 1954 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Paintings - Mg Sein Gyi, 4 total, 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Pan American World Airways, 1953 - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Pan American World Airways - Domain of Phoebus Apollo: Ruler of the Sun and Heaven certificate, 1954 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Power of Attorney by Individual for the Collection of Checks Drawn on the Treasurer of the United States, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Print ephemera, ca. 1953 - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pyidawtha Handicap Tennis Tournament, Mixed Doubles, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - The Rangoon Boy Scouts' Association, ca. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The Registration of Foreigners Rules, 1948. Temporary Certificate of Registration, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Science Department, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Social and Reading Club, University of Rangoon, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - State High School, ca. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - United States Education Exchange Grant, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - United States Educational Foundation in Burma, 1953 - 1962, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Sub-series 3: Ephemera
    - Mother-of-pearl lapel pins, ca. 1953
  - Sub-series 4: Slides
    - Burma, slide carousel 1 of 3 (125 slides total), 1953 - 1954
    - Burma, slide carousel 2 of 3 (118 slides total), 1953 - 1954
    - Burma, slide carousel 3 of 3 (28 slides total), 1953 - 1954
    - Margaret Aung Thwin (1 slide), 1967 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 5: Photographs
    - Central State High School, Rangoon (3 images total), 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Union of Burma, ca. 1953 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Resistance Day Parade, 27 March, 1954, 1954 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Photo Album (brown cover), ca. 1953 - 1954
    - Photo Album (blue/grey cover), ca. 1953 - 1954
    - Burmese Photographs, loose, 1954 - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Series 4: Teaching / Principalship
  These are papers and photographs from Mary Florence's long career as an educator and principal for Chicago Public Schools (CPS). The bulk of these materials come from her tenure at Luke O'Toole School in what is today the West Englewood community. There are also papers from Philip Murray School and Hyde Park High School, as well as general materials from CPS and Illinois educational foundations.
  - Sub-series 1: Luke O'Toole School
    - O'Toole School, "Teen Problems", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Beaver Pathway, 1965 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Clippings, 1965 - 1979 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Luke O'Toole Parent-Teacher Association, District 25 Program Year Book 1968 - 1969, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - O'Toole School Record Book, Nov. 1972, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - O'Toole Piper, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Mailing List, O'Toole School, ca. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - O'Toole Piper, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Luke O'Toole School Newspaper, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Performance Appraisal Form, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "The best person I would most like to talk to" by Eileen Johnson, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Luke O'Toole Elementary School Graduation Exercises, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Resignation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Retirement Memory Book, photographed + compiled by D. Flynn & D. Tannheimer (see also: Oversized FFC3, D3 & Photo Album (green cover, silver stripes), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Mary F. O'Shea Luke O'Toole School Sliver Burdett Co. binder, n.d. (Box FFC3, D3)
  - Sub-series 2: Subject Files
    - Board of Education, City of Chicago, 1942 - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chicago Public Schools (CPS) - Teacher's Certificate, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - CPS - Notice of Teacher Transfer, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - CPS - Principal's Certificate, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - The Hydeparker, Vol.85, No.11, 1957 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Hyde Park High School A Cappella Choir gives Joy to the World, Galewood Records, Inc. (10" vinyl), ca. 1957
    - Hyde Park High School A Cappella Choir, Jerome K. Ramsfield, Director, Century Record Co. (10" vinyl, blue), 1958
    - George Peabody College for Teachers, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Philip Murray School, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Illinois Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1965 - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Board of Education Service Recognition, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chicago Board of Education Service Recognition, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New City Lions Club, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Public School Teachers' Pension and Retirement Fund of Chicago, 1973 - 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chicago Board of Education Service Recognition, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Push for Excellence Inc. - Award For Excellence, 1981 (Box FFC3, D3)
    - Chicago Public Schools Employees' Service Recognition Reception, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chicago Principals Association, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Chicago Public Schools, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Retired Teachers Association of Chicago, 1986 - 2009 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Aquin Guild - Distinguished Service Award (see also: Oversized), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series 3: Ephemera
    - CPS service pins, 25 Years; 30 Years; 35 Years, ca. 1975 - 1985
    - Illinois Congress of Parents and Teachers Life Member pin, n.d.
  - Sub-series 4: Slides
    - Philip Murray School (33 slides total), 1961
    - Headstart (2 boxes, 77 slides total), 1965
    - O'Toole - Jean Rose 7 + 7 Club (17 slides), 1966
    - O'Toole (3 boxes, 68 slides), 1966
    - O'Toole, May 1966 (4 slides total), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Headstart (37 slides total), 1967
    - O'Toole (19 slides total), 1967
    - O'Toole, slide carousel 1 of 2 (89 slides total), 1971 - 1972
    - O'Toole, June 1972 (11 slides total), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - O'Toole, Int'l Fair - Bazaar slide carousel 2 of 2 (125 slides total), 1972 - 1973
    - O'Toole, 1975 August (7 slides total), 1975 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - O'Toole - Kindergarten Graduation (21 slides total), 1975
    - 2EII Christmas 75 incl. O'Toole Christmas Assembly, Don City, 400 E.R. slide carousel (61 slides total), 1975
    - O'Toole - Kindergarten (13 slides total), 1978
    - O'Toole (13 slides total), 1981
  - Sub-series 5: Photographs
    - O'Toole School, 1966 - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - O'Toole Teachers Luncheon, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Principals, District 15, 1969 - 1975, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - O'Toole Photo Album, folder 1 of 2, 1982, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - O'Toole Photo Album, folder 2 of 2, 1982, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - O'Toole School - "Be the Best of Whatever You Are", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - O'Toole School, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - O'Toole School, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - O'Toole Retirement Party, ca. 1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - O'Toole School, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Series 5: Rosary College / Dominican University
  This slim set of materials is primarily comprised of items from Mary Florence's graduation, and from her subsequent attendance at various college Reunions over the years.This slim set of materials is primarily comprised of items from Mary Florence's graduation, and from her subsequent attendance at various college Reunions over the years.
  - Fete Night, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Commencement, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Bachelor of Arts, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Reunion 1991, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reunion 2001, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Reunion 2006, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 2008 - 2009, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Annual Fund, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mazzuchelli Heritage Society, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bookmarks, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 1: Photographs
    - Graduation and Candid, 1941, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Reunions, 1991, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series 6: Outer Drive East Condominium
  These files come from Mary Florence and Mary Jane's
  - Reunions, 1991, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chicagoland Survey Co. Plat of Survey of 12th Floor, 1973 (Box FFC3, D3)
  - Outer Drive East Condominium Initial Offering, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Outer Drive East Condominium Brochure (see also: Oversized FFC3, D3), ca. 1973 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - By-laws of the 400 Condominium Association, ca. 1973 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Escrow Agreement and Tax Assessment, 1973 - 1974 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Loans - Clyde Savings / Mid-City National Bank, 1973 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cook County Property Tax Bills, 1973 - 2008 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The 400 Condominium Association - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Homeowner's Guide to Property Assessment, Cook County, ca. 1976 - 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Outer Drive East Condominium Stationery, ca. 1970s (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Appraisal Certificate, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box FFC3, D3)
  - The 400 Condominium Association - Monthly Assessments, 1985 - 2002 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Loans - River Valley Savings Bank, 1991 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Senior Tax Credit, 1992 - 2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)